<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>kimo&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>http://mohadkamil.github.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on kimo&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Jun 2018 15:20:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://mohadkamil.github.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>VSTS as CMS</title>
      <link>http://mohadkamil.github.com/posts/vsts-cms/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jun 2018 15:20:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mohadkamil.github.com/posts/vsts-cms/</guid>
      <description>Blogging for the duration of two posts -that&amp;rsquo;s a long time in blog years :)-, I thought I would share the blogging platform I use, and it would be good to talk about the steps required to publish a post, for me I came to choose and love hugo to build this blog, Hugo is static site generator written in go, the idea is simple but powerful, you write your content in markdown and through Hugo these posts (or whatever content) get compiled to static code -HTML,CSS and javascript in the case of web-, having your blog served as only static files makes it super fast and it plays great with CDN like Cloudflare which I am planning on using in the near future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Migrating to VSTS</title>
      <link>http://mohadkamil.github.com/posts/vstsmigration/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 20:21:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mohadkamil.github.com/posts/vstsmigration/</guid>
      <description>At work a need arose for migrating a project with 4 years worth of history from our on-premise TFS to the online visual studio team services (VSTS), completing the migration, I thought I would share the workflow and steps for migrating a project from local TFS to VSTS, and the gotchas and consideration you need to be aware of.
But first, Why would you want to migrate? It could be for a couple of reasons, one of them is to tap into the up to date features of the online VSTS, while the on-premise offering of TFS gets updated, the cadence at which the online counterpart gets updated is much much higher.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello world</title>
      <link>http://mohadkamil.github.com/posts/helloworld/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2016 23:23:41 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mohadkamil.github.com/posts/helloworld/</guid>
      <description>he first program you write when you learn a new programming language is the famous Hello world program , and as such, this is my hello world blog post , I will return soon to talk more about many interesting topics , but now I was able to say Hello to the world , and that’s enough for now.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>